HESSAM IMEN

FRONTEND DEVELOPER

0

0403762697



Sydney Olympic Park



hessam.imen@gmail.com



www.linkedin.com/in/hessam-imen



github.com/hessamimen

SUMMARY

Front-End Developer with experience in creating and maintaining a better code base for reusability. Passionate about learning and development with a desire to tackle more complex problems and continue to find ways to maximise user efficiency.

EXPERIENCE

Renomate App (https://renomate.app)

Frontend Developer

Jan 2022 - Now

- Designing and developing dynamic web pages using HTML, CSS. JavaScript and React.
- Implementing responsive web design principles to ensure that our company website renders well across multiple devices.
- Collaborating with other developers to plan and implement solutions to web application issues.
- Planning and prioritising projects and tasks while working under pressure to meet deadlines.
- Working in an agile team and updating our tasks in the Jira environment.
- Keeping up-to-date with the latest technology and programming trends.
- Converting video, audio, written, and graphic components into compatible formats for the web.
- Bridging the gap between graphic design and technical implementation.

Academy Xi Australia, Sydney (https://academyxi.com/)

Software Engineering Intensive Participant.

Feb 2022 - Now

- Nominated to enrol the Software Engineering Transform program, facilitated by Flatiron School. Whilst this is also education, the commitment is a minimum of 30 hours per week with task and project requirements.
- Learning backend development skills to become a Full-stack developer along with creating several web pages from scratch - using CSS3, HTML5, Vanilla JavaScript, VS Code, React.js, Git terminal (Git Bash), GitHub, NPM.

KEY SKILLS

- HTML
- · CSS
- BOOTSRAP
- JAVASCRIPT
- REACT
- RUBY
- STYLED COMPONENT
- MATERIAL UI

CERTIFICATES

Codecademy:

- HTMI
- CSS
- JavaScript
- React

FUTURE SKILLS

- REDUX
- RAILS
- SASS
- HTTP
- RACK
- SINATRA

EDUCATION

ACADEMY XI - SYDNEY Software Engineering Certificate

<u>University of Manchester</u> *MSc Project Management*

IAUM

BSc Civil Engineering

2020 - 2022

Freelance web developer

- Designing and developing dynamic web pages using HTML, CSS, JavaScript.
- · Communicating with clients and manage ongoing projects and maintenance requests.
- · Identifying and taking action for issues and opportunities to ensure continuous improvement.
- Projects been involved in:
 - http://www.faranail.dk/
 - https://mazraeyeroghan.com/
 - https://azepco.com/
 - https://renomate.app/